Justin!
Quick, honey, take my picture.
I got the pyramid in my hand.
亲爱的 快帮我照张相
我把金字塔托在手上呢
Justin, you get back here right now!
Justin 你马上给我回来
No, stop!
停
- No, no! Stop him!
- Go back! Don't climb!
- 拦住他
- 回来 不要爬上去
Wait, wait.
等一下 等一下
Hold on. Easy, little boy.
站住 慢慢来 小家伙
Okay, stop, child! Stop right there. No!
好 停 孩子 就在这儿停住 不要!
No, no, no! There he goes.
不好了 他掉下去了
Justin!
I've got him! I've got him!
我抓住他了 我抓住他了
Outrage in Egypt tonight
as it was discovered
今晚在埃及发现了一起令人震惊的事件
that the Great Pyramid of Giza
had been stolen
吉萨金字塔被偷走了
and replaced by a giant inflatable replica.
取而代之的是一个巨大的充气复制品
There is panic throughout the globe
as countries and citizens
这引起了全球的恐慌
与此同时各国人民
try to protect their beloved landmarks.
也誓要保护他们的标志性建筑
Law enforcement still has no leads,
执法部门仍然没有找到任何线索
leaving everyone to wonder,
which of the world's villains
这不禁让人们好奇究竟是哪一个
恶贯满盈的歹徒
is responsible for this heinous crime?
要对这起极不道德的犯罪负责任呢
And where will he strike next?
他的下一个目标又是什么呢
(我今天倒霉透了)
I'm having a bad, bad day
It's about time that I get my way
(是时候我行我素了)
Steamrolling whatever I see
(要破坏我所见的一切)
Freeze ray! Freeze ray! Freeze ray!
冰冻射线  冰冻射线  冰冻射线
I'm having a bad, bad day
(我今天倒霉透了)
If you take it personal, that's okay
(如果你要往心里去 那也无所谓)
Watch, this is so fun to see
(瞧 这多有趣)
Despicable me
(卑鄙的我)
Morning, Gru!
早上好 Gru
How you doing?
你好吗?
Hello, Fred.
你好 Fred
FYI, your dog has been leaving
little bombs all over my yard,
顺便让你知道一下
你的狗在我的院子里到处便便
and I don't appreciate it.
可我并不需要狗便便
Sorry. You know dogs.
They go wherever they want to go.
对不起 你知道狗狗总是随心所欲的
Unless they're dead.
除非他们死了
I'm joking!
骗到你啦
Although, it is true.
Anyway, have a good one.
虽然事实是这样
好啦 祝你今天愉快
Okay. Yeah.
好的
Steamrolling whatever I see
(破坏我所看见的一切)
Despicable me
(卑鄙的我)
I'm having a bad, bad day
(我今天倒霉透了)
(如果你要往心里去 无所谓)
If you take it personal, that's okay
Despicable me
(卑鄙的我)
You've got to be pulling on my leg!
别这样搞我吧
Hello!
有人吗?
Cookies for sale.
要买小饼干吗
Go away. I'm not home.
走开 我不在家
Yes, you are. I heard you.
你在的 我听到你声音了
No, you didn't. This
不 你听错了
is a recording.
这是答录机
- No, it isn't.
- Yes, it is.
- 不 不是
- 是的
听好了 请留言 哔
Watch this. Leave a message, beep.
Goodbye, recorded message.
再见 录音器
Agnes, come on.
Agnes 走吧
Kyle!
Bad dog! No! No, no. Sit. My muffin.
可恶的狗 不  不
坐下 我的松饼
Gru!
Gru
Dr Nefario.
Nefario博士
I know how you must be feeling.
我知道你的感受
I, too, have encountered
great disappointment,
我也觉得非常遗憾
but in my eyes,
you will always be one of the greats.
但在我眼中 你永远是最棒的
What? What happened?
发生什么事了?
It's all over the news!
所有的新闻都在报道
Some fella just stole a pyramid.
有个家伙把金字塔偷了
They're saying he makes
all other villains look
他们说其他坏人和他比起来显得
lame.
逊色
Assemble the minions!
集中小奴才!
Minions, assemble!
小奴才 集合!
Okay. Okay.
好的 好的
Hey!
嗨
Looking good, Kevin!
How is the family? Good?
Kevin 看上去不错嘛
家里人都好吗
All right.
好的
That's my Billy boy! What up, Larry?
我的小宝贝 Larry 好吗?
Hello, everybody!
大家好
Yeah, all right!
好啦
Simmer down. Simmer down!
安静 安静
Thank you, okay.
谢谢
Now, I realise that you guys probably heard
我想你们都听说了
about this other villain
who stole the pyramids.
关于金字塔被别的坏人偷走的事了
Apparently, it's a big deal.
很显然 这是件大事
People are calling it
the crime of the century and stuff like that.
大家都说这是一个划时代的创举啥的
But am I upset? No, I am not!
但我生气了吗?  不 我没有!
一点点
A little,
but we have had
a pretty good year ourselves,
但是我们这一年的成绩相当不错
and you guys are all right in my book.
我认为你们都很棒
No, no raises!
没有加薪
You're not going to get any raises.
你的工资是不会加的
What did we do?
我们都干了些什么
Well, we stole the Times Square JumboTron!
我们偷了时代广场的大电视屏幕!
Nice!
正点!
That's how I roll.
看我多厉害
Yeah, you all like watching football
on that, huh?
你们都喜欢用它看橄榄球比赛　是吧
But that's not all.
不止这些
We stole the Statue of Liberty,
我们还偷了自由神像
the small one from Las Vegas.
在拉斯维加斯的那座小的
And I won't even mention the Eiffel Tower!
Also Vegas.
更别提艾菲尔铁塔了
也是拉斯维加斯的
Okay, I wasn't going to tell you
about this yet,
好了 本来我不打算告诉你们的
but I have been working
on something very big!
我正在进行一项非常伟大的计划
Something that will blow this pyramid thing
out of the water!
和这件事毕金字塔这事马上就要变浮云啦
And thanks to the efforts
of my good friend Dr Nefario...
同时非常感谢我的好朋友
Nefario博士的大力相助
Thank you!
谢谢
There he is.
他在那
He's styling.
很有型啊
Now, we have located a shrink ray
我们在一个秘密实验室里发现了
in a secret lab,
and once we take this shrink ray,
一种收缩射线 一旦我们得到它
we will have the capability
我们就有能力
to pull off the true crime of the century.
创造真正的划时代犯罪行为
We are going to steal...
我们准备要偷取...
Wait, wait! I haven't told you what it is yet.
等一下 我还没告诉你们是什么
Hey.
嗨
Dave, listen up, please.
Dave 听好了
Next, we are going to steal,
下一步 我们将要去偷
pause for effect,
来个定格效果
the moon!
月亮!
And once the moon is mine,
一旦月亮到我手
the world will give me
whatever I want to get it back!
他们就会对我有求必应以换回月亮
And I will be the greatest villain of all time!
而我将成为世界上最伟大的坏人
That's what I'm talking about.
这才是我想要的
Yes?
什么事
Hello, Gru?
I've been crunching some numbers,
喂 Gru? 我算了一下
and I really don't see how we can afford this.
我们负担不起进行计划的费用
It can't be done. I'm not a miracle worker.
这个计划完成不了 我不是魔术师
Hey, chillax.
放心
I'll just get another loan from the bank.
They love me!
我会去银行再贷款的 他们喜欢我
Edith, stop it!
Edith 别再这样了
What? I'm just walking.
干嘛? 我走路而已
- Hi, Miss Hattie. We're back.
- Hattie老师 我们回来了
Hello, girls!
姑娘们 你们好
Anybody come to adopt us
while we were out?
我们不在的时候有人来领养我们吗
让我想一想
Let me think.
No!
没有
Edith! What did you put on my desk?
Edith 你放什么在我桌上呢
A mud pie.
泥巴馅饼
Edith 你永远不会被领养的 知道吗
You're never gonna get adopted, Edith.
You know that, don't you?
- Yeah, I know.
- Good.
- 我知道
- 好极了
So, how did it go, girls?
Did we meet our quotas?
孩子们进行得怎样了
达到目标了吗
Sort of.
差不多
We sold 43 mini-mints, 30 choco-swirlies,
and 18 coco-nutties.
我们卖了四十三个迷你薄荷 三十个巧克力圈圈
还有十八个可可果仁
Okay.
好
Well, you say that like it's a great sale day.
嗯 好像你们卖得很好嘛
Look at my face!
看着我
Do you still think it's a great sale day?
你们还认为是这样吗
Eighteen coco-nutties.
十八个可可果仁
I think we can do a little better than that,
don't you?
我觉得我们可以做得更好一点 是吗
Yeah.
是呀
We wouldn't want to spend the weekend
in the Box of Shame, would we? No.
你们周末不会想要呆在盒子里反省吧
- No, Miss Hattie.
- 不 Hattie老师
Okay, good. Off you go.
Go clean something of mine.
好极了 可以走了 帮我整理一下东西
- Hi, Penny.
- 嗨 Penny
嗨 你们好
Hi, guys.
嗨 妈妈 对不起
我本来想打电话的 可是...
Hello, Mom. Sorry, I meant to call, but...
I just wanted to congratulate you
on stealing the pyramid.
我只是想恭喜你偷了金字塔
That was you, wasn't it?
是你干的 是吧?
Or was it a villain who's actually successful?
还是另外一个成功的混混干的?
Just so you know, Mom,
I am about to do something
妈 告诉你 我将要做
that's very, very big, very important.
一件非常非常大和重要的计划
如果你知道了一定会感到很骄傲
When you hear about it,
you're going to be very proud.
Good luck with that. Okay, I'm out of here.
祝你好运 我要走了
(恶魔银行)
Gru to see Mr Perkins.
Gru 我约了Perkins先生
Yes, please have a seat.
好的 请坐
That's one small step for man,
这是人类的一小步
one giant leap for mankind.
全人类的一大步
Ma, someday I'm going to go to the moon.
妈 我有一天也要上月球
I'm afraid you're too late, Son.
儿子 来不及了
NASA isn't sending the monkeys any more.
美国宇航局不再送猴子到那儿做实验了
Hey.
我正在申请一个新的坏人贷款
用Vector这个名字
I'm applying for a new villain loan.
Go by the name of Vector.
这是个数学术语
It's a mathematical term,
a quantity represented by an arrow,
with both direction and magnitude.
表示方向和数量
Vector! That's me,
Vector 那就是我
'cause I'm committing crimes
with both direction and magnitude.
因为我犯的罪都是有来头的
Oh, yeah!
Check out my new weapon.
看看我的新武器
Piranha gun! Oh, yes!
水虎鱼枪 酷!
Fires live piranhas. Ever seen one before?
No, you haven't. I invented it.
以前有看到过吗
你肯定没看过 我发明的
Do you want a demonstration?
Shoot! So difficult, sometimes,
to get the piranha back inside of my...
糟糕 有时候把鱼塞回枪膛很难...
Mr Gru, Mr Perkins will see you now.
Gru先生 Perkins先生现在可以见你了
So, all I need
所以 我要的
is money from the bank to build a rocket.
就是从银行借钱造一架火箭
- And then, the moon is ours.
- Wow!
- 然后 月亮就是我们的了
- 哇
Well, very nice presentation.
嗯 陈述得非常好
I'd like to see this shrink ray.
我希望可以看一下这个收缩射线
Absolutely! Will do. Soon as I have it.
没问题 我很快就会有了
You don't have it?
你还没有?
And yet you have the audacity
to ask the bank for money?
你这样也有脸向银行借钱?
Apparently.
显然易见的
Do you have any idea of the capital
that this bank has invested in you, Gru?
你知道这间银行已经投资
在你身上多少资金了吗 Gru
With far too few of your sinister plots
actually turning a profit.
你有什么阴谋坏事做了是赚钱的
How can I put it? Let's say this apple is you.
我怎么投?  比方说这个苹果是你
If we don't start getting our money back...
如果我们不将借出去的钱拿回来
Get the picture?
知道后果了吗
Look, Gru, the point is,
there are a lot of new villains out there,
Gru 我要说的是
新坏人不断涌现
younger than you, hungrier than you,
他们比你年轻 比你饥饿
younger than you.
比你年轻
Like that young fellow out there
named Vector.
象那边的小男孩叫Vector
He just stole a pyramid!
他刚偷走了金字塔
I've got it. I've got it.
了解 了解
So, as far as getting money for the rocket...
所以 谈到借钱造火箭...
Get the shrink ray, then we'll talk.
先把收缩射线弄到手 我们再谈吧
Suckers!
白痴
We got it!
我们拿到了
What?
什么
Hey! Hey! What! Hey!
嗨 嗨 嗨
No, no, no!
不 不 不
You!
你
Now, maybe you'll think twice
before you freeze someone's head!
在你冰冻别人的脑袋前你要三思
So long, Gru!
再会 Gru
Quick! We can't let him get away!
快 不能让他跑了
Up ahead! Up ahead!
高一点 高一点
开火 开火
Fire! Fire, now!
You missed me!
没打到我
Come to papa!
哥拼了
Take that.
拿着吧
真可爱
How adorable.
Got you in our sights!
看到你了
Like taking candy from a...
就像把糖果从...
What?
不是吧
Hey, Gru!
嗨 Gru
Try this on for size!
试一下这个
That's weird. What is going...
真奇怪 发生什么。。。
This is claustrophobic!
这是幽闭恐怖症
No, no, no!
不 不是的
Too small! This is too small for me!
太小了  这个太小了
I hate that guy!
我讨厌那家伙
...and please watch over us, and bless
that we'll have a good night's sleep.
请看护着我们 保佑我们睡个好觉
And bless that while we're sleeping,
no bugs will crawl into our ears
还有保佑我们睡着的时候虫子
不会爬进我们的耳朵
and lay eggs in our brains.
和在我们的脑袋里下蛋
Great. Thanks for that image, Edith.
谢谢你的想象力 Edith
And please bless
that someone will adopt us soon,
请保佑我们很快就会被领养
and that the mommy and daddy will be nice
新爸爸妈妈对我们很好
and have a pet unicorn.
还有一只独角兽宠物
Amen.
阿门
- Amen.
- 阿门
Unicorns, I love them
unicorns, I love them
独角兽 我最喜欢他们了
独角兽 我也喜欢他们
uni, uni, unicorns
I love them
独角兽 我爱他们
uni, unicorns, I could pet one
独角兽 我可以养一只
If they were really real
如果真有这东西
And they are
他们是真的
So, I bought one so I could pet it
我买了一只我就可以养它了
Now it loves me
Now I love it
它爱我 我爱它
Don't you... What the...
你...
祝你好运 小姑娘
Good luck, little girls!
Whoa! Cool.
哇 酷
Hi! We're orphans
from Miss Hattie's Home for Girls.
我们是女孩之家的孩子 我们是孤儿
关我什么事 走开
- I don't care. Beat it!
- Come on!
We're selling cookies
so, you know, we can have a better future.
我们在卖饼干做慈善 为了孩子的未来
- 等等 你们有没有椰子果仁?
- 有啊
- Wait, wait! Do you have coco-nutties?
- Yeah.
Light bulb.
灯泡
Dr Nefario!
Nefario博士
I'm going to need a dozen tiny robots
disguised as cookies!
我需要一打的乔装成饼干的小机器人
- 什么
- 饼干机器人
- What?
- Cookie robots!
- Who is this?
- Oh, forget it.
- 这是谁?
- 算了
Well, it appears you have cleared
our background check,
嗯 你已经通过我们的背景调查
Gru医生
Dr Gru.
And I see you have made a list
我看到你写了一张清单
of some of your personal achievements.
列出一些你的个人成就
Thank you for that. I love reading.
谢谢 我很喜欢读书
And I see you have been given
the Medal of Honor
我也留意到你被授予过勋章
and a knighthood.
和骑士头衔
- Me, me, me.
- 我 我 我
Kevin?
You had your own cooking show
你有自己的烹饪节目
and you can hold your breath
for 30 seconds?
你还可以三十秒不呼吸?
It's not that impressive.
没什么了不起的
Idiot!
傻瓜
- Fight! Fight! Fight! Fight!
揍它 揍它...
What in the name of... What?
以什么的名义...什么
Well, here's the dealio.
是这样的
Things have been so Ionely since my wife,
生活显得很孤单自从我的太太
Debbie, passed on.
Debbie 不在了
It's like my heart is a tooth,
就像我的心是一颗牙
and it's got a cavity
that can only be filled with children.
然后长了蛀牙 只能由孩子们来填补牙洞
对不起
I'm sorry.
You are a beautiful woman.
Do you speak Spanish?
你是位漂亮的女士
你讲西班牙语吗
Do I look like I speak Spanish?
我看上去像会讲西班牙语吗
You have a face como un burro.
你的脸太美了
Well, thank you!
谢谢
Anyway, can we proceed with this adoption?
我们可以继续领养手续了吗
太激动了
So, so excited!
Please tell Margo, Edith and Agnes
to come to the lobby.
请叫Margo Edith和Agnes到大厅来
I bet the mom is beautiful!
我打赌妈妈一定很漂亮
我说爸爸的眼睛会闪闪光
I bet the daddy's eyes sparkle.
他们的房子一定都是用
Gummi Bear糖做的
I bet their house is made of Gummi Bears.
I'm just saying it'd be nice.
我只是说说而已
My caterpillar never turned into a butterfly.
我的毛毛虫永远也不会变成蝴蝶了
That's a Cheeto.
那是一个Cheeto(芝士做的零食)
Well, Debbie was a very lucky woman.
Debbie真是幸运
Who's Debbie?
谁是Debbie?
Your wife.
你太太
Hi, girls!
嗨 姑娘们
姑娘们 给你们介绍这是Gru先生
Girls, I want you to meet Mr Gru.
He's going to adopt you.
他准备收养你们
And he's a dentist!
他是个牙医
Yeah!
Hi. I'm Margo. This is Edith.
嗨 我是Margo 这是Edith
And that's Agnes.
那是Agnes
I got your leg, I got your leg!
抓住你的腿了 抓住你的腿了
Okay, that is enough, little girl.
好了 够了 小姑娘
- Let go of my leg. Come on. You can do it.
- Higher!
- 放开我的腿 快点 放手
- 高一点
- Higher!
- Just release your grip. Wow!
- 再高一点
- 快放手吧
How do you remove them?
Is there a command?
怎么让她们撒手呢
要发命令么
Some nonstick spray?
还是有什么不粘手的喷剂
Crowbar?
难道要用撬棍
Okay, girls, let's go.
好了 孩子们 咱们走吧
Oh, yeah!
Pretty impressive!
酷毙了
What are you looking at?
你看什么呢
Boo-ya!
砰砰
You got shrunk, tiny mouthwash!
你被缩小啦 小小漱口水
Take that!
受死吧
You done been shrunk!
你被缩小啦
Yello?
你好
I got the shrink ray, all right.
我拿到缩小射线枪啦 那是当然
No, I'm not playing with it.
没 我没拿它玩
Gru?
Gru
Don't make me laugh! No.
别跟我开玩笑了
P.S., he is not getting the moon,
顺便说一句 他才偷不了月球呢
and P.P.S., by the time I'm done with him,
顺便说第二句 等我好好教训他
he's gonna be begging for mercy.
他会向我求饶的
Okay, bye.
好了 拜拜
Look at you, a little tiny toilet
for a little tiny baby...
瞧你 小小的马桶给小小的孩子用
Curse you, tiny toilet!
去你的 小马桶
Okay, here we are.
好啦 我们到了
Home sweet home.
到家了 甜蜜的家
So, this is, like, your house?
那么 这就是 你的家喽
Wait a sec...
等一下
You're the guy
who pretended he was a recorded message!
你就是那个假装自己是答录机的家伙
No, that was someone else.
不 你搞错了
Can I hold your hand?
我可以握住你的手吗
No.
不行
When we got adopted by a bald guy,
I thought this'd be more like Annie.
我们被一个光头的家伙收养的时候
我还以为我们会像Annie日记里的主角呢
No, hey!
不 喂
Kyle, these are not treats. These are guests.
Kyle 她们是客人 不是玩具
Girls, this is Kyle, my
姑娘们 这是Kyle 我的
dog.
狗
毛毛狗狗
Fluffy doggy!
What kind of dog is that?
它是什么品种
He is a... I don't know.
他应该是 我也不知道
Do you really think that this is
an appropriate place for little kids?
你真觉得这里适合住小孩子吗
'Cause it's not.
看来不是啊
No! No! Stay away from there!
不 不 别去那儿
It's fragile.
这个经不起折腾的
Well, I suppose the plan will work with two.
这个 只有2个孩子
计划应该还是能够进行的吧
Hey! It's dark in here.
嘿 这里好黑
It poked a hole in my juice box.
它把我的果汁盒戳了个洞
As you can see,
你们瞧
I have provided everything
a child might need.
我已经准备好一个孩子可能需要的一切了
All right.
好啦
Okay. As I was saying... Hey!
好 我刚刚说什么来着  嘿
Somebody broke that.
有人把这个打碎了
Okay, okay.
Clearly, we need to set some rules.
好吧 好吧
看来  我们需要定些规矩
Rule number one.
第一条
You will not touch anything.
不准摸任何东西
What about the floor?
那地板呢
Yes, you may touch the floor.
嗯   那个可以摸
What about the air?
那空气呢
Yes, you may touch the air!
嗯   那个也可以摸
What about this?
那这个呢
- Where did you get that?
- Found it.
- 那个你哪儿来的
- 我找到的
Okay. Rule number two.
You will not bother me while I'm working.
好吧  规矩二
我工作的时候你们不能烦我
Rule number three.
规矩三
You will not cry or whine or laugh or giggle
不能哭 抱怨 大笑或者傻笑
or sneeze or burp or fart!
还有打喷嚏 打嗝和放屁
So, no, no, no annoying sounds. All right?
反正就是一丁点烦人的声音都不能有 知道吗
Does this count as annoying?
这个也算烦人吗
Very!
很烦人
I will see you in six hours.
6个小时后见
Okay, don't worry.
Everything's going to be fine.
好了 别担心 会没事的
We're gonna be really happy here.
Right? Agnes?
我们会在这儿过得很开心的
对吧 Agnes
Question. What are these?
请问 这些是什么
A dozen boogie robots! Boogie!
12个跳舞机器人 会跳舞的哦
Look at this. Watch me!
看这个  看我的
饼干机器人  我说的是饼干机器人
Cookie robots. I said cookie robots.
Why are you so old?
为什么你  这么老
Okay. I'm on it.
好的 我这就开始做
Hello?
有人么
TV!
电视
What is that?
那是什么
- Look at that!
- That is cool!
- 看那个
- 酷毙了
Come on!
来吧
I don't think he's a dentist.
我觉得他不牙医
We've been working on this for a while.
为这个我们已经干了好一段时间了
It's a anti-gravity serum.
这是反重力血清
I meant to close that.
He'll be all right, I'm sure.
我本想着关上那个的
他会没事的 我敢肯定
- Do the effects wear off?
- So far,
-药效会消失么
-到现在为止
no. No, they don't.
没有 没消失
And here, of course,
is the new weapon you ordered.
而这个 就是你要的新武器啦
No, no.
不 不
I said "dart gun," not... Okay.
我说的是“飞镖手枪” 不是…
好吧 就这样吧
Oh, yes. 'Cause I was wondering
是吧 难怪了 我还在想
under what circumstances
would we use this?
这个东西你要什么时候用嘞
But, anyway.
不过呢 这个
What I really wanted to show you was this.
我真正想让你看的是这个
Now those are cookie robots!
这才是饼干机器人嘛
La, la, la, la
I love unicorns
啦啦啦啦  我爱独角兽
What are you doing here?
I told you to stay in the kitchen!
你们在这儿干什么
我不是让你们待在厨房吗
We got bored. What is this place?
我们觉得无聊嘛
这是哪儿
Can I drink this?
这个能喝么
Do you want to explode?
你想爆炸么
Gru!
Gru
Get back in the kitchen!
给我回厨房去
- Will you play with us?
- No.
- 你能跟我们玩么
- 不行
- Why?
- Because I'm busy.
- 为什么
- 因为我很忙
Doing what?
忙什么呢
Okay, okay, you got me.
好吧好吧 被你发现了
The dentist thing is more of a hobby.
做牙医只是我的一个爱好
In real life, I am a spy.
在真实生活中 我是个间谍
And it is top secret,
and you may not tell anybody,
这个是最高机密哦
你可不能告诉任何人
- because if you do...
- What does this do?
- 因为如果你说出去的话
- 这个是干什么用的
Hey!
嘿
My unicorn!
我的独角兽
You have to fix it.
你得修好它
Fix it? Look, it has been disintegrated.
By definition, it cannot be fixed.
修好 听着 它已经被分解了
意思就是说 它没法修了
That's freaking me out. What is she doing?
她吓到我了 她在干嘛
She's gonna hold her breath
until she gets a new one.
在得到一个新玩具之前她会一直憋着气
It is just a toy. Now stop it!
那就是个玩具 别闹了
Okay, okay! I'll fix it!
好吧好吧 我来修
Tim    Mark    Phil
Tim! Mark! Phil!
This is very important.
这次的任务很重要哦
You have to get the little girl
a new unicorn toy.
你们要给小女孩找个新的独角兽玩具
Hey, hey, hey! A toy!
嗨 嗨 嗨 玩具
Go, and hurry!
赶紧的
What are those?
它们是什么
They are my cousins.
他们是我的堂弟
Jerry! Stuart!
Jerry  Stuart
Watch them,
and keep them away from me, please.
盯着他们  让他们离我远点
- Wow!
- 哇
It was your cousin's idea.
那是你堂兄的主意
What?
什么
Okay, bedtime.
好了 要睡觉了
Not you two!
你倆不用啦
Okey-dokey. Beddie-bye.
All tucked in. Sweet dreams.
好的 晚安
都躺好了 好梦
Just so you know,
告诉你
you're never gonna be my dad.
你绝不可能成为我爸爸
I think I can live with that.
没关系 我受得住
Are these beds made out of bombs?
这些床是炸弹做的么
Yes, but they are very old
and highly unlikely to blow up.
是的 但是它们很旧 不大可能爆炸
But try not to toss and turn.
不过最好不要乱翻身
Cool.
酷毙了
- 能给我们读睡前故事吗
- 不行
- Will you read us a bedtime story?
- No.
But we can't go to sleep
without a bedtime story.
可不听睡前故事 我们睡不着
Well, then it's going to be
a long night for you, isn't it?
这个 看来今晚是个漫漫长夜了
So, good night, sleep tight,
and don't let the bed bugs bite.
好吧  晚安 好好睡吧
别让床虱咬到了
Because there are literally
thousands of them.
因为这里真的有成千上万的床虱哦
And there's probably
something in your closet.
在衣橱里搞不好还有别的什么东西呢
He's just kidding, Agnes.
他只是开玩笑的 Agnes
It's beautiful.
真漂亮
Girls, let's go.
姑娘们 我们走吧
Time to deliver the cookies!
送饼干的时间到了
Okay. But first, we're going to dance class.
好吧  但我们得先去上舞蹈课
Actually, we're going to have to skip
the dance class today.
实际上我们今天就不去上舞蹈课啦
Actually, we can't
skip the dance class today.
实际上我们今天不能不去上舞蹈课
We have a big recital coming up.
我们在为一个大的演出准备呢
- We're doing an excerpt from Swan Lake.
- Yeah, Swan Lake!
- 我们将会表演天鹅湖的片段
- 是的 天鹅湖
That's fantastic. Wonderful.
那很好 太好了
But we're going to deliver cookies! Come on!
但是我们要去送饼干 来吧
No.
不
No?
不去么
We're not going to deliver cookies
until we do dance class.
上完舞蹈课再去送饼干
Really?
确定么
Well, I am not driving you to dance class.
那么 我是不会开车送你们去上舞蹈课的
So if you want to go,
you are going to have to walk yourselves.
想去的话 你们就做得自己走
你们在干嘛
What are you doing?
Walking to dance class.
走路去上舞蹈课
Ya? Okay, fine.
啊 好吧 好
You just keep walking,
because I'm really not driving you!
继续走啊
我才不会开车送你们
Okay.
好啊
You're going to suffer the wrath of Gru!
你们小心别把我Gru惹毛啦
Seriously, I'm going to count to three!
说真的  我数三下
And you had better be in this car!
到时候你们最好乖乖坐在车上
Here we go! One! Two!
现在开始 一  二
...three, four and five.
三 四 五
And lift, and stretch.
抬手 伸臂
And one, and two...
一 二
- Here you go.
- What is it?
- 给你
- 这是什么
Your ticket to the dance recital.
You are coming, right?
给你参加舞蹈汇演的门票
你会来的 是吧
Of course, of course.
当然 当然了
I have pins and needles that I'm sitting on.
我现在坐如针毡
Pinkie promise?
拉钩保证
Oh, yes. My pinkie promises.
哦 好的 拉钩保证
All right.
Our first customer is a man named Vector.
好吧 我们的第一个顾客
是个叫做Vector的人
But he's a V.
但是他的名字首字母是V
You know, we're supposed
to start with the A's.
你知道的 我们应该从A开始
Then we go to the B's. Then we...
然后是B 接着呢
Yes, yes! I went to kindergarten.
I know how the alphabet works!
是的 是的 我上过幼儿园
我很清楚字母表
I was just thinking
我只是觉得
that it might be nice
to deliver Mr Vector's first.
咱们先给Vector先生送
That is all.
没别的
Almost over. It's almost over.
快结束了 就快结束了
Girls, welcome back
to the fortress of Vector-tude!
女孩们 欢迎回到Vector-tude的城堡
Do you have my cookies for me?
饼干给我带来了么
Four boxes of mini-mints, two toffee totes,
四盒小薄荷糖 两大包乳脂糖
two caramel clumpies
and fifteen boxes of coco-nutties.
两桶黄油奶糖和十五箱椰蓉糖
Exactly. I'd like to see somebody else
order that many cookies.
很好 不知有没有第二个人订购那么多饼干
Not likely.
应该没有
Name one person
who ordered more cookies than me.
能说出一个比我订购更多饼干的人不
That'll be $52.
一共52块
Right.
好的
Seven, eight, nine...
七 八 九
Tic Tacs! Where was I?
滴答 我数到哪儿啦
Seven, eight, nine...
七 八 九
Why are you wearing pyjamas?
你为什么穿着睡衣呢
These aren't pyjamas!
This is a warm-up suit.
这不是睡衣
这是热身运动服
- What are you warming up for?
- Stuff.
- 你做热身运动干嘛
- 做事
What sort of stuff?
什么事
Super-cool stuff you wouldn't understand.
你不懂的超级酷的事
Like sleeping?
比方睡觉么
They are not pyjamas!
这不是睡衣
Here you go, 52 big ones.
给你 52块大洋
Bye!
拜拜
Come on!
拜托
What the...
搞什么
Quiet down, fish!
安静 你这鱼
Down, boy!
别闹了 你
We did it! Come on, girls, let's go!
我们成功了 姑娘们 咱们闪人
But what about the other people
who ordered cookies?
但是其他订购了饼干的人怎么办呢
Life is full of disappointments
人生总是充满了失望
for some people.
对于某些人来说
Don't do that!
别那么做
Super Silly Fun Land! Can we go? Please?
超级笨笨乐园
我们能去玩么 可以么
No.
不行
But we've never been.
And it's the funnest place on earth!
可我们从来没去过呢
那是地球上最好玩的地方啦
Don't care.
我不在乎
- Please?
- 求求你啦
- 求求你
We'll never ask for anything else,
ever again!
我们再也没有别要求啦
什么别的要求都不提好不
- Pretty please?
- Please?
- 你最好的啦
- 好不好嘛
- 去吧
- Come on!
Light bulb.
好主意
Come on!
去吧
Goodbye, have fun.
再见 玩得开心哈
Sorry, dude.
They can't ride without an adult.
对不起伙计
得有个大人跟她们一起坐
What?
什么
Oh, my gosh!
哦 我的天啊
Look at that fluffy unicorn!
瞧那个可爱的毛毛独角兽
He's so fluffy, I'm gonna die!
它好多毛毛啊 我都要兴奋死了
You've gotta let us play for it!
让我们玩这个来赢它好不
No, no, no.
不 不 不
Come on!
来吧
How much for the fluffy unicorn?
这个毛茸茸的独角兽多少钱
Well, it is not for sale.
额 那个不卖的
But all you gotta do to win it
is knock down that little spaceship there.
不过只要你把那个小飞船击倒
就能把它赢回家
It's easy!
很简单
Yay!
耶
Again!
再来一次
- Wait!
- Come on. One more time!
- 等等
- 求你了 再玩一次吧
Just one more.
就最后一次
I accidentally closed my eyes.
我刚刚碰巧闭上眼睛了
- I hit it! I hit it!
- That was cool.
- 我打着了 打着了
- 太牛了
Whoa, whoa, whoa. What was that?
喔 喔 喔 怎么回事
She hit that. I saw that with my own eyes.
她打到了 我亲眼看见的
Hey, buddy,
let me explain something to you.
嘿 伙计
听我给你解释
You see that little tin spaceship?
You see how it's not knocked over?
看到那个锡制小飞船了吧
看到它还没被打翻么
Do you know what that means, professor?
知道那意味着什么吗 教授
It means you don't get the unicorn!
这意味着你不能得到那只独角兽
Somebody's got a frowny face.
看来有人要不爽啦
Boo! Better luck next time!
嘘 祝你下次好运吧
Okay, my turn.
好 轮到我了
Knocked over!
搞定
- It's so fluffy!
- Yeah!
- 好多毛毛啊
- 是啊
That was awesome!
太帅了
You blew up the whole thing!
你把整个摊子都炸飞啦
Let's go. Let's try another game!
走吧 我们去玩另一个游戏
Gru, do you mind if I have a quick word?
Gru能跟你说句话么
Okay, girls, go play.
好啦 孩子们 去玩吧
I got the shrink ray!
我拿到缩小射线枪了
Cotton candy!
棉花糖要么
We have 12 days
until the moon is in optimum position.
还有12天月亮就会转至最合宜的位置
We can't afford any distractions!
我们不能分心啊
Get me Perkins.
给我接Perkins
Sorry to bother you, Mr Perkins,
不好意思打扰你 Perkins先生
but I figured that you would want to see this!
不过我想你需要看看这个
What?
什么
Well done, Gru. Rather impressive.
不错啊Gru 非常厉害
Now, the rest of the plan is simple.
剩下的事情就很简单啦
I fly to the moon. I shrink the moon.
我飞去月球  把它缩小
I grab the moon. I sit on the toilet.
拿到它 坐上马桶
What?
什么
Sorry. Sorry!
不好意思 对不起
Could you excuse me for just one second?
我离开一小会哦
I told you not to touch my things.
告诉过你们别碰我的东西
I told you, I told you.
I've told you a thousand times.
我已经和你们说过几千遍了
Hey, can we order pizza?
嘿 我们能点比萨吃么
Pizza? You just had lunch.
比萨 你们才吃过午饭啊
Not now, for dinner.
不是现在吃 是当晚餐
Dinner?
晚餐啊
Just... Fine, fine, fine, whatever.
Just get back in there!
好吧 好 随便
现在赶快进去吧
Can we get stuffed crust?
能点包心卷边的么
- Stuffed crust!
- 包心卷边
I'll stuff you all in the crust!
再叫我就把你们包起来卷进边里
You're funny!
你好搞笑哦
Just don't come out of that room again!
别再跑出来啦
All right.
好的
Sorry about that. Where were we?
不好意思哈  我们说到哪了
You were sitting on the toilet.
你坐在马桶上
No, no, no! No, I'm sorry.
It was a little attempt at humour.
不 不 不 真不好意思
那只是想幽默一下
I know how much you like to laugh
我知道你有多爱笑
inside. Now, I was saying...
在心里笑
好了 我刚刚说到
You don't seem terribly focused, Gru.
你好像很心不在焉呀 Gru
00:52:52,440 --> 00:52:54,317
你似乎没怎么用心做事啊 Gru
Believe me, I am completely focused.
相信我 我一向很用心做事的
- Hello!
- What?
- 你好啊
- 什么?
That guy is huge!
这个人好大个头呀
- Are we on TV?
- What are those? Children?
- 我们是上电视了吗
- 这都是谁啊?你孩子?
What are you doing?
I told you to stay out of here!
你们在干嘛?
我不是说了要你们出去吗!
No, no, no!
别 别 别
Freeze ray!
冰冻射线!
Mr Gru?
Gru先生?
Okay.
好了
As I was saying...
就像我所说的...
No need to continue. I've seen quite enough.
你不必说了 我已经看够了
- But my plan...
- Is a great plan.
- 但是我的计划...
- 很棒的计划
我喜欢你计划里的一切 除了一件事
I love everything about your plan,
except for one thing.
You.
就是你
Look, Mom, I drew a picture of me
landing on the moon!
看 妈妈 我画了张我登月的图!
Look, Mom, I made a prototype of the rocket
out of macaroni!
看 妈妈
我用通心粉做了个火箭模型!
Look, Mom, I made a real rocket
based on the macaroni prototype!
看 妈妈
我参照通心粉的模型做了个真的火箭!
I don't understand.
我不明白
Let's face reality, Gru.
面对现实吧 Gru
You've been at this for far too long
with far too little success.
虽然你一直在努力
可是总不能成功
We're gonna put our faith,
our money, into a...
我们将把我们的信心
我们的钱放到一个...
Well, a younger villain.
一个更年轻的坏蛋身上
But I...
但我...
It's over. Goodbye, Gru.
都结束了 再见 Gru
Now, I know there have been
some rumours going around
我知道最近出现了些谣言
that the bank is no longer funding us.
说银行不会再资助我们了
Well, I am here to put those rumours to rest.
我就是来澄清谣言的
谣言是真的
They are true.
In terms of money,
就资金而言
we have no money.
我们是没有钱了
So how will we get to the moon?
那我们要怎么上月球呢
The answer is clear.
答案再明显不过了
我们去不了了
We won't.
We are doomed.
我们失败了
Now would probably be a good time
to look for other employment options.
你们是时候去找份新工作了
I know.
我知道
I have fired up my resume
as I suggest that all of you do, as well.
我已经把我的简历给烧了
我也建议你们这么做
What is it?
怎么了
Can't you see that I am
in the middle of a pep talk?
没看见我正在激励大家吗
Yes!
好呀
Yes, we will build our own rocket
好的 我们来建自己的火箭
using this and whatever else we can find!
用这个 还有任何我们能找到的东西
Grab everything!
Hit the junkyards! Take apart the cars!
把所有东西都拿上
去废品回收站  把那些旧车给拆了
Who needs the bank?
谁还需要银行啊
Let's go. Let's go!
我们走 我们走
Mom! What are you doing here?
妈妈  你在这干嘛?
And here he is in the bathtub.
这是他正在浴缸里的照片
Look at his little buns.
看看他的小屁屁
Mom.
妈妈
Not cool.
一点都不好玩
And here, he's all dressed up
in his Sunday best.
这张 他穿上了他最好的衣服
He looks like a girl!
他看起来像个女孩
Yes, he does. An ugly girl!
没错  是的  一个难看的女孩
You're funny!
你真可爱
Yes! Mine's shaped like a dead guy!
真棒  我的看起来像个死人
Mr Perkins, your son is here.
Perkins先生 你儿子来了
Send him in.
让他进来
Hey, Dad.
嗨 爸爸
你想见我?
You wanted to see me?
- Yes, I did, Victor.
- I am not Victor any more.
- 没错 Victor
- 我已经不叫Victor了
Victor was my nerd name. Now I am Vector!
Victor这名字傻死了
现在我叫Vector
Sit down!
坐下!
Do you know where the shrink ray is?
你知道缩小激光枪在哪吗
就在我那放着呢
Duh! Back at my place.
Oh, is that right?
Back at your place? That's cool.
是吗 在你那放着吗
那真是不错啊
I guess Gru must just have one
that looks exactly like it!
那Gru是正好有了个一样的咯!
What the... Those girls sold me cookies!
等下...这些小女孩卖过饼干给我
你知道这个偷月计划有多赚钱吗
Do you have any idea
how lucrative this moon heist could be?
I give you the opportunity of a lifetime,
我给你了次千载难逢的机会
and you just blow it!
你却白白断送了
- No, I didn't.
- Oh, really?
- 不 我没有
- 是吗
You just wait
until Gru sees my latest weapon.
你就等着让Gru看我的终极武器吧
Squid-launcher! Oh, yeah!
鱿鱼发射器  欧耶
There's a squid on my face!
怎么有只鱿鱼盖我脸上了
Don't worry.
别担心
The moon is as good as ours.
月亮会是我们的
Come on now, it's bedtime.
好了 过来 该上床睡觉了
Did you brush your teeth?
Let me smell. Let me smell.
你刷牙没?
让我闻闻 让我闻闻
You did not!
你没刷
Put on your PGs.
Hold still. Okay, seriously! Seriously!
穿上你们的睡衣
别捣乱了 好了 我说真的 真的
This is beddie-bye time, right now.
I'm not kidding around. I mean it!
该睡觉了 现在就去
我没在开玩笑 快睡
- But we're not tired!
- Well, I am tired.
- 我们还不累呢
- 但我累了
Will you read us a bedtime story?
能给我们讲个睡前故事吗
No.
不行
Pretty please!
求你了
The physical appearance of the "please"
makes no difference.
说多少个"求你了"也没用
It is still no, so go to sleep.
回答还是不行 所以快睡觉
But we can't. We're all hyper!
我们睡不着 我们还这么兴奋
And without a bedtime story,
we'll just keep getting up and bugging you.
如果不讲睡前故事的话
我们就会不断的起床打扰你滴
All night long.
整个晚上
Fine.
好吧
好 好 沉睡的小猫
All right, all right. Sleepy Kittens.
Sleepy Kittens?
沉睡的小猫?
- What are these?
- Puppets.
- 这是什么
- 手指玩偶
You use them when you tell the story.
你可以戴着它们给我们讲故事
Okay, let's get this over with.
好吧 让我们开始吧
"Three little kittens loved to play,
they had fun in the sun all day.
"有三只小猫 它们很爱玩耍
它们在阳光下疯玩了一整天"
"Then their mother came out and said,
'Time for kittens to go to bed."'
"这时它们的妈妈来了说
'小猫们该睡觉了‘'"
Wow! This is garbage.
You actually like this?
哇 这故事真烂
你们真的喜欢这个?
Keep reading!
继续讲啊
- Come on!
- All right, all right, all right.
- 快点继续
- 好 好 好
"Three little kittens started to bawl,
"这三只小猫就开始哭着说"
"'Mommy, we're not tired at all.'
"'妈妈 我们还一点都不想睡呢'"
"Their mother smiled and said with a purr,
"它们的妈妈笑了笑 回答说"
01:01:04,800 --> 01:01:08,315
"'好吧 但你们至少
要先梳理梳理自己的毛'"
"'Fine, but at least
you should brush your fur."'
Now you brush the fur.
现在你帮它们梳毛
This is literature?
这也算儿童文学?
A 2-year-old could have written this.
All right.
两岁的小孩子都能写了 好吧
"Three little kittens with fur all brushed
"三只小猫把毛都梳理了"
"said, 'We can't sleep, we feel too rushed! '
"然后说 '我们睡不着
我们还兴奋着呢'"
"Their mother replied, with a voice like silk,
"她们的妈妈柔声回答到"
"'Fine, but at least
you should drink your milk."'
"'好吧 那你们应该至少先喝个牛奶吧'"
Now make them drink the milk.
现在给它们喝牛奶吧
I don't like this book.
This is going on forever.
我不喜欢这书
这没完没了的
"Three little kittens, with milk all gone,
rubbed their eyes and started to yawn.
"三只小猫喝了牛奶后
眼皮开始打架 打起了哈切"
"'We can't sleep, we can't even try.'
Then their mother sang a lullaby.
"'我们还是睡不着 我们还不困'
然后它们的妈妈唱了支摇篮曲 "
"'Good night kittens, close your eyes.
Sleep in peace until you rise.
"'小猫们晚安 闭上眼睛吧
愿你们一觉安睡到天亮"
"'Though while you sleep, we are apart,
"'尽管当你们睡着时
我们不在一起"
"'your mommy loves you with all her heart."'
"'但你们的妈妈
永远全心全意地爱你们'"
The end. Okay, good night.
故事讲完了 好了 晚安
- Wait!
- What?
- 等等
- 怎么了又?
What about good night kisses?
还有晚安吻呢
No, no. There will be no kissing or hugging
or kissing.
不行 不行
不会有晚安吻 抱抱还有吻之类的
He is not gonna kiss us good night, Agnes.
他不会给我们晚安吻的 Agnes
I like him. He's nice.
我喜欢他 他挺好的
But scary.
就长得有点吓人
Like Santa!
像圣诞老人!
Only 48 hours till the launch,
and all systems are go.
离火箭发射只有48小时了
整个系统已经准备好了
About that,
关于这个
I was thinking that maybe
we could move the date of the heist.
我在想可不可以推迟几天
Please tell me this is not as a result
of the girls' dance recital, is it?
千万别告诉我这是因为要去看
这几个小姑娘的舞蹈表演 好吗
No, no, no!
不是 不是 不是
The recital? Don't... That's stupid!
舞蹈表演会?
绝对不是...这么傻的玩意
I just think it's kind of weird
to do it on a Saturday.
我只是觉得在星期六发射有点奇怪
I was thinking,
maybe a heist is a Tuesday thing, right?
我只是觉得
或许星期二去偷月不错 对吗
Gru, you and I have been
working on this for years.
Gru 我们都为这工作了几十年了
It's everything we've dreamed of.
这就是我们的夙愿
Your chance to make history,
这是改写历史的机会
become the man who stole the moon!
成为偷月的第一人!
But these girls
are becoming a major distraction!
但这些女孩会让你分心的
They need to go.
她们得离开
If you don't do something about it,
then I will.
如果你不采取行动的话
我就会了
I understand.
我明白了
Good.
很好
Butt.
屁股
All right.
Now, when we put our cups together,
好了  当我们碰杯时
we will make the "clink" sound
with our mouths.
我们要说"干杯"
Ready? Edith?
准备好没 Edith?
- Clink.
- 干杯
There we go. And now we drink.
来吧 现在喝了它
And Agnes?
接下来 Agnes?
- Clink.
- 干杯
Very good!
很好!
Excuse me, girls.
很抱歉 姑娘们
Come on!
拜托
Don't worry, I'll be back. Keep clinking.
别担心 我马上就回 你们继续干杯
- Clink, clink.
- 干杯 干杯
Miss Hattie, what are you doing here?
Hattie小姐 有何贵干
I'm here for the girls. I received a call
that you wanted to return them.
我是为姑娘们来的
我接到电话说你想把她们送回去
And also,
I did purchase a Spanish dictionary.
还有 我专门买了本西班牙字典
I didn't like what you said.
我不喜欢你说的
But...
但...
I will get the girls ready.
我会让姑娘们准备好的
Don't let her take us, Mr Gru!
别让她带我们走 Gru先生
Tell her you wanna keep us.
告诉她你想让我们留下来
All right, girls. Come on, let's go.
好了 姑娘们 来吧 我们走
Goodbye, Mr Gru. Thanks for everything.
再见了 Gru先生
感谢你所做的一切
I did it for your own good.
我是为你好
Come on, let's go get that moon.
来吧 让我们偷月吧
Right.
好的
What is this for?
这是干嘛的
The recital?
舞蹈表演会?
I am the greatest criminal mind
of the century.
我可是本世纪最伟大的罪犯
I don't go to little girls' dance recitals!
我才不会去
这些小女孩的舞蹈表演会呢
Opening launch bay doors.
Commencing launch sequence.
开启顶上舱门
开始发射程序
And we are good to go
in T minus 10 seconds.
我们将在十秒后出发
Ten, nine, eight, seven,
十 九 八 七
six...
六...
Oh, yeah!
Nice work, Doctor. All systems go.
干的漂亮 博士 一切正常
Boo-ya!
My flight suit.
我的飞行服
Oh, yeah! Once again, the mighty...
再来一次 强大的...
I've got it!
我拿到了!
I've got the moon!
我拿到了月亮!
I can make it!
我还可以赶上的
- Wait a minute!
- Kevin!
- 等下
- Kevin
Come on, come on!
快点 快点!
He's still not here.
他还没来
Why would he come? He gave us up.
他为什么要来?
他已经不要我们了
But he pinkie promised!
但他已经和我拉钩答应的了
Girls, girls, places!
姑娘们 姑娘们 要开始了
No, we can't start yet!
We're still expecting someone.
还不能开始
我们还在等一个人
Can we just wait a few more minutes?
能再等等吗
All right. But just a few more minutes.
好吧 但只有几分钟
He's not coming, guys.
他不会来的 大家
Gru! Gru, can you hear me?
Gru  Gru 能听到我说话吗
Quick, we have to warn him, and fast!
快 我们得警告他 要快!
Okay, okay. There's the library.
好的 好的 这是图书馆
That's Third Street. The dance studio...
那是第三大街 舞蹈厅...
There! There! There it is!
那! 那! 在那!
Sorry, buddy. Show's over.
抱歉 兄弟 演出已经结束了
Over?
结束了?
(Margo Edith和Agnes的爸爸)
(带上月亮 V)
Vector, open up!
Vector 快开门
First give me the moon. Then we'll talk.
先把月亮给我
然后我们再谈
- Mr Gru!
- Zip it, Happy Meal.
- Gru先生
- 闭嘴 小甜心们
Now, the girls.
现在 可以放了她们了吧
事实上 我觉得我还要多留她们一阵
Actually, I think I'll hold on to them
a little while longer.
No!
不行!
Oh, yeah! Unpredictable!
当然可以  难以预料吧
Listen close, you little punk.
给我听好了 你个小废物
When I get in there,
you are in for a world of pain!
要是我进去了 你就惨了
I'm really scared!
我好害怕哟
He is gonna kick your butt.
他绝对会把你臭扁一顿的
What? He punched my shark!
什么 他居然打了我的鲨鱼
There he is!
他在那
Hang on, Gru.
抓紧 Gru
Oh, no!
噢 不要!
Vector has the girls. Go!
姑娘们在Vector手上 快走!
What happened to the ship? It's big again!
这船怎么回事  怎么又变大了
- Not as big as the moon is going to be!
- What?
- 反正不会比月亮大
- 什么
The larger the mass of an object, the quicker
the effects of the shrink ray wear off!
你缩小的对象越大
缩小射线的作用消失得就越快
I call it the Nefario Principle.
我称之为Nefario定律
I just came up with it now, actually.
其实 我也是刚想到的
Oh, no!
不是吧
Did you see that?
你们看见没?
- Vector! Help!
- Vector!
- Vector!  救命!
- Over here!
- Hey!
- 快看这
- 嗨
What are you girls doing back there?
你们几个在那搞什么鬼?
The moon!
月亮!
Watch out!
小心!
Get as close in as you can.
快点靠近啊
You got it.
行了
- Mr Gru, up here!
- Mr Gru!
- Gru先生 我们在这
- Gru先生
Okay, girls! Girls!
好了 姑娘们  姑娘们
- You're going to have to jump.
- Jump?
- 你们得跳下来
- 跳下去?
Are you insane?
你疯了吗
Don't worry, I will catch you.
别担心 我会接住你们的
You gave us back!
你都抛弃我们了
I know, I know.
And it is the worst mistake I ever made.
我知道 我知道
这是我犯过的最大的错
But you have to jump now.
但你们得马上跳下来
It'll be okay.
会没事的
Okay, girls.
好了 姑娘们
Jump now!
快跳
Margo, I will catch you.
Margo 我会接住你的
And I will never let you go again.
而且再也不会放手
- Not so fast!
- No!
- 别想这么快走
- 不要!
Let me go!
让我走
Margo!
I'm coming, Margo. Hang on!
我来了 Margo 抓住!
I got you.
抓到你了
No!
不!
Oh, poop.
天那
This time, good triumphs,
这次 是好消息
and the moon has been returned
to its rightful place in the sky.
月亮又回到了它在天上的位置
But once again, law enforcement is baffled,
leaving everyone to wonder,
但再一次的 政府部门也很困惑
大家都在想
who is this mysterious hero?
这次的神秘英雄是谁?
And what will he do next?
他的下一步行动是什么呢
Okay, girls. Time for bed.
好了 姑娘们 该睡觉了
- Come on! We want a story.
- Three sleepy kittens!
- 行了  我们想要睡前故事
- 三只沉睡的小猫
Oh, no! Sorry. That book was
accidentally destroyed maliciously.
不行  抱歉
那本书碰巧被完全损坏了
Tonight we are going to read a new book.
今晚我们要讲个新故事
This one is called
叫做
One Big unicorn by... Who wrote this?
一只大的独角兽 作者是...
谁写的呢?
Me! I wrote it. Look, it's a puppet book!
哦 我!  我写的 看
还是个有手指玩偶的书哟!
Here, watch this.
来 看看这个
That's the horn!
这是角
This is gonna be the best book ever!
这肯定会是最好的书!
Not to pat myself on the back,
but, yes, it probably will be.
我也不想吹牛
但 没错  或许会是
Here we go.
我们开始吧
"One big unicorn, strong and free
"有一个大的 强壮的 自由的独角兽"
"thought he was happy as he could be.
"他总是自以为快乐的生活着"
"Then three little kittens came around
"突然三只小猫闯进了他的生活"
"and turned his whole life upside down."
"然后改变了他整个的生活"
Hey, that one looks like me!
嗨 那只猫跟我好像!
No, what are you talking about?
These are kittens!
不是 你在说什么呢
这是些小猫
Any relation to persons living or dead
is completely coincidental.
如有雷同 肯定纯属巧合
"They made him laugh.
"它们让他笑"
"They made him cry.
"让他哭"
"He never should have said goodbye.
"他最不该的就是和它们说再见"
"And now he knows he could never part
"现在他知道"
"from those three little kittens
"他永远不能和这三只"
"that changed his heart.
"改变了他的心的小猫分离"
"The end."
"故事讲完了"
Okay, all right. Good night.
好了 晚安
I love you.
我爱你
I love you, too.
我也爱你
No, no!
不行 不行
All right.
好吧
Didn't I get you already?
我不是已经亲过你了吗
They're very good!
她们跳得很好
I'm so proud of you, Son.
我真为你骄傲 儿子
You've turned out to be a great parent!
你成了一个很棒的家长
Just like me.
就像我一样
Maybe even better.
或许比我还要好
No, I'm fine. Go ahead.
不 谢了 你们继续吧
No, no, no!
不 不 不
Hey, Carl! Hey.
嗨 Carl! 嗨
No, no, no.
不 不 不
Me, me, me.
我来 我来 我来
John?
No, no. Me, me, me.
不 不 我来 我来 我来
Oh, poop.
噢 天那
Oh, no!
不!
Stop! Stop!
停  停
Hello, I am Gru.
你好 我是Gru
Back to work, back to work! Back to...
去工作 去工作! 去...